

#### CANDIDATE, MASTER'S DEGREE, APPLIED CRYPTOGRAPHY

## Summary .

I am a Master of Science (Computer Science) student at the University of Melbourne researching applied cryptography with Vanessa Teague. I have been a programmer for years, and am passionate about education, security, and privacy. Research interests include zero-knowledge proofs, authenticated data structures, and multiparty computation.

## **Education**

University of Melbourne Parkville VIC 3010

M.Sc. (COMPUTER SCIENCE)

B.Sc. (MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS)

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATICS

2015-2018

## **Experience**

### **University of Melbourne**

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jul 2019 - Present

- Working with Prof. Shanika Karunasekera to develop and deploy a large distributed cloud-based system for data collection and analytics. The
  project allows large volumes of data (e.g. from social media) to be categorised by topic and analysed for patterns.
- Working as a full-stack developer on a Java server and two front-end GUIs in Java and React. Responsibilities include finding and fixing issues, as well as developing new features and system monitoring scripts.
- Assisted the security research group with grant applications.

### **Blueprint for Free Speech**

Developer Liaison Jul 2019 - Present

- Created a revived GitHub presence and website for the Ricochet end-to-end encrypted chat service operating over Tor.
- · Helped update the C++ codebase and installation scripts to work with the latest versions of Tor and operating systems.

### **University of Melbourne**

HEAD TUTOR (OBJECT-ORIENTED SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT)

Jul 2016 - Nov 2019

- Managed the tutoring team for a core subject with hundreds of students, liaising between students, tutors, and lecturers.
- Developed major assignments for students, including specifications, marking criteria, and testing methodology.
- Delivered one to two lectures per semester on software tools and alternative paradigms while also teaching two to three tutorials per week.
- Excellence in Tutoring Award (2017), School of Computing and Information Systems

#### **Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre**

SUMMER STUDENT Nov 2018 - Feb 2019

- Worked as a full-stack developer consulting with scientists to build a web application using Python and MySQL, allowing users to work with a
  database for prostate cancer samples and patients.
- · Created interactive search and visualisation tools to collate and present large amounts of data in an easy-to-digest format.

## **Honors & Awards**

2020 **Student Registration Grant,** IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy

Oakland, California,

U.S.A.

2019

## **Publications**

University of Melbourne

• Eleanor McMurtry, Olivier Pereira, Vanessa Teague. When is a test not a proof? In Submission.

# **Projects**

## CUDA CCL (https://github.com/noneuclideangirl/cuda-upad/)

University of Melbourne 2019

- A tool to perform connected-component labelling on a large image very quickly using a GPU. Written using CUDA and C++, implementing an algorithm from the literature in a way that had not been successfully done before to maximise performance.
- · Major project for the graduate subject Parallel & Multicore Computing.

## Extra-Dimensional Box (https://github.com/noneuclideangirl/extra-dimensional-box)

• An implementation of the Bitbox protocol by Dr Aaron Harwood, a peer-to-peer file-sharing system.

- A Java networking project designed to be efficient and reliable, for use on small computers such as a Raspberry Pi.
- Major project for the graduate subject Distributed Systems.

MAY 7, 2020 ELEANOR MCMURTRY · CV